# **Thomas Loch**

Thomas\_Loch@hotmail.com | linkedin.com/in/thomaslloch/ | +31 6 44 287 288 | thomasloch.nl

# **Summary**

IoT Developer with a focus on hardware. Experienced with software / cloud workflows of Microsoft, along with Azure Dev-Ops build pipelines. Previous experience in the electronic manufacturing industry, focusing on pcb development and manufacturing proficiency. Skilled with C#, ASP.NET Core, Altium Designer, Autodesk Inventor, Azure Dev-Ops, Agile/scrum methodology. Strong professional with a Bachelor of Aviation from Griffith University.

# **Education**

# 2019, Working Talent, The Netherlands

IoT Masterclass

#### 2018 - On Hold, University of Southern Queensland, Australia

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) Majoring in Computer Systems GPA: 6.29

#### 2009 - 2012, Griffith University, Australia

Bachelor of Aviation, Graduate Diploma of Flight Management GPA: 4.6

# 2007 - 2008, Metropolitan South Institute of TAFE

Certificate III in Computer Aided Drafting

# 2004 - 2008, Loganlea State High School

High School Certificate Year 12

# **Certificates**

Microsoft 70-483 Programming in C#

# **Work Experience**

# 03/2019 - 11/2019, Atos (via Working Talent)

IoT Developer

- Medical Smart Fridge: This project revolved around the tracking and tracing of medicine, through the use of RFID technology. The purpose was to keep tight control over controlled drugs, be able to pinpoint which fridge the medicine resides in, and keep track of expiration dates / storage conditions. I was responsible for hardware procurement, assembly, and programming.
- Connectivity Platform: This project aims to serve as a single cloud based point of access for various data sources. I become involved with the project as scrum master, and programmer for small battery operated hardware. I worked with various communication platforms such as LoRa, NB-IoT, and BLE (Bluetooth).
- Tools Used: C#, ASP.NET Core, C++, Arduino, Git, Scrum, Azure, SQL, Azure devops pipelines.

## 11/2017 - 01/2019, Loch Engineering

Owner

- Design and assembly of custom mechanical keyboards
- Tools Used: Altium Designer, KiCad, Autodesk Inventor, C#, C++, Git.

#### 07/2016 - 11/2017, Pacific Data Systems Australia Pty. Ltd.

Production Technician | R&D Technician

- Assembly and testing of company products, using machines and hand tools.
- Assembly of pcb's, using a pick and place machine (Autotronik BA385V2), and reflow oven.
- Assembly of small R&D pcb batches, using hand tools, down to 0402 sized components.
- o Programming, fault finding and fixing of assembly and R&D pcb's.
- Designing circuit boards, to a strict set of design standards based on product needs.
- Maintaining an up to date inventory of all components, and upkeeping the BOM of all company electronic products.
- Making inhouse modbus testing software using C#
- o Tools Used: Altium Designer, Autodesk Inventor, C#, Git.

# 11/2013 - 07/2016, Aldi

Trainee Store Manager (from 10/2014) | Workplace Health & Safety Officer

- Exceptional customer service.
- Responsibility of all store money.
- Ensuring shifts happen as scheduled, within operational guidelines at all times.
- Staff training, and maintenance of standards among all staff.

# **Skills**

# Languages

- English
- Dutch

#### Computer software | languages

- AutoCAD 2d/DXF preparation for production.
- Inventor 3d modelling and sheet metal design.
- o Altium 2-4 layer design, down to 0402 size
- C/C++ Custom keyboards, usb io boards
- C# Testing software, using RS485/Modbus
- HTML/JavaScript Basic website design, pure JavaScript
- Latex Math assessment, resumes & cover letters
- Git multi user projects

#### Other

I have run my own business designing and selling custom keyboards

# **Aviation**

#### License

Commercial Pilot License 11/04/2012 | Training Completed at the Airline Academy of Australia Private Pilot License 18/07/2011 | Training Completed at the Airline Academy of Australia Total Time: 240 Hrs | PIC: 80 Hrs

# **Rating & Endorsements**

- Single Engine (<5,700 kg)</li>
- Multi Engine Command Instrument Rating
- Beechcraft Duchess BE76
- Manual Propeller Pitch Control
- Retractable Undercarriage
- Tailwheel Undercarriage

# **Flight Hours**

0	Total time:	240 Hrs
0	Pilot in Command:	80 Hrs
0	Multi Engine:	30 Hrs
0	Night Time:	12 Hrs
0	Beechcraft Duchess:	30 Hrs
0	Cessna 172RG:	49 Hrs
0	Cessna 172R/S:	154 Hrs
0	Citabria:	7 Hrs

# References

# **Guido van der Sluis**

14.0 / IoT Business Technology Consulting+31 6 3028 0307 | guido.vandersluis@atos.net

#### **Martin Akman**

Software Engineer, Pacific Data Systems Australia Pty. Ltd. +61 7 3361 2000 | makman@pacdatasys.com.au

# **David Hugman**

Production Manager, Pacific Data Systems Australia Pty. Ltd. +61 7 3361 2000 | dhugman@pacdatasys.com.au